搞定
And bingo.
放下枪
Drop the gun!
站住
Stop!
== 海军罪案调查处:洛杉矶 第五季 第8集 ==
【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献
== 翻译：一直向左走 理性动物 瑶小瑶 尧之雪 蛋蛋 ==
== 校对：金多多 天之行者 时间轴：天之行者 ==
== 后期&统筹：尧之雪 封装：天之行者 ==
本字幕仅用于交流 学习之用
禁止用于任何商业用途 否则后果自负
啊 漂亮小橱柜
Ah. Nice cabinets.
- 你自己做的  - 从刨木头开始都是
- You built those yourself?  - From scratch.
- 哇 做了多久  - 大约一个月
- Wow. How long did that take?  - About a month.
- 一个月  - 是呀
- A month?  - Yeah.
为啥你不干脆雇一个专业工匠呢
Why didn't you just hire a professional?
雇工匠的钱的一小部分足够我自己做了
I spent a fraction of what it would cost by doing it myself.
是啊 但是你花的时间是一个工匠工作时间的四倍
Yeah, but you spent quadruple the time a professional would have.
你想说啥
And what's your point?
我的意思是如果你雇一个工匠
Well, my point is that if you'd hired a pro,
你就会有更多的时间来做你喜欢做的事情了
you could have spent more time doing the things you love.
是啊 我自己喜欢做橱柜呀
Yeah, and by doing it myself,
我给我爱的人存了更多的钱
I saved more money for the ones I love.
我就不明白了
I just don't get it.
你当然不明白了 你又没有孩子
Of course you don't-- you don't have kids.
我说 你用钱都干嘛了
I mean, what do you spend money on?
我们都一样的工资
We have the same salary.
Hetty实际上送给你一个房子
Hetty practically gave you a house.
还有我还经常买单
And yet I'm always picking up the check.
难道我要阻止你大方吗
Who am I to deny your generosity?
另外 是你自己无能
Besides, this is about your inability
放弃掌控 雇一个工匠
to relinquish control and hire a professional.
我听到Sam又自己动手了
Am I hearing that Sam is DIY'ing again?
哦 是呀
Oh, yeah.
他刚用了一个月做了个架子
He just spent a month building some shelves.
橱柜
Cabinets.
那就花了我几周而已 现在 你就说是一个月了
And it was only a couple of weeks. Now, you said a month.
为啥你不雇个工匠呢
Why don't you just hire a professional?
- 用那些时间放松一下  - 正是
- Take that time for yourself to relax.  - Exactly.
这又是一个单身汉的观点
This coming from another one who lives alone.
啥
What?
手工让我放松
Building relaxes me.
另外 对一个男人来说
Besides, it's good for a man to know
他能用自己的手制作是极好的
that he can create with his hands.
我用我的手了啊 我用手
I use my hands. I use my hands
拿起电话 打给工匠
to pick up the phone and call a professional.
然后我用我的手
And then I use my hand
刷我的信用卡来付工钱
to use my credit card and pay that professional.
- 这有啥好笑的  - 我告诉你笑点在哪儿
- Where's the fun in that?  - I'll tell you where the fun is.
笑点就是 呃 我们花钱雇来的人就能帮我们干活的时候
The fun is in the, uh, mojitos that we're sipping
我们就能畅享莫吉托(一种鸡尾酒)了
while the guy that we're paying is doing the work.
那就是我想说的
That's what I'm talking about.
就是这意思
不对 我完全赞同Sam
No, I totally agree with Sam.
美女都喜欢男人制作东西 好性感
A woman likes a guy who can build things; it's sexy.
源于为她遮风避雨的吸引力
It stems from a primal attraction for shelter.
我盖过一个树屋 这性感吗
I built a tree house once-- how is that for sexy?
我保证那玩意儿肯定不在了
I guarantee that's not still standing.
- 或许不在了 不过在那地方我失去了  - 太过了
- Maybe not, but it's where I lost my... TMI.
控制 我原本要说的 我没抓牢 摔下来
Grip-- I was gonna say it's where I lost my grip, fell down,
断了我的尾椎骨 我还有疤 你想看吗
broke my coccyx-- I got a scar; you want to see it?
不想
No.
乌拉
Whoa.
这是
Is that...
摩斯密码
Morse code?
我们有案子了
"We got a case."
是Eric 他在叫我们去控制中心
Eric. He's calling us up to ops.
我觉得是时候干预一下(Eric)了
I think it's time for an intervention.
祝你好运 我要花点时间
Good luck with that. I have a small window
去联系莫利纳 卡特尔的线人
to contact the Molina Cartel informant--
我要去见他
I'm gonna take it.
我在控制中心给你打掩护
I'll cover you in ops.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
这就像一个轻度按摩
It's like a gentle massage.
给我的臀大肌
It's in my glutes.
恶
Ew.
怎么了 今早我还做了下蹲
What? I did squats this morning.
是吧 呀吼吼 嘿哈哈
Yeah? Couple of yah-ho-ho, little hee-haw-ho's.
- 天哪 那真好  - 恶
- God, that's nice!  - Ew.
嘿 让我看看你的手机 我能用
Hey, let me see your phone. I can use one
- 一个臀瓣一个  - 真恶心
- for each glute.  - That's just gross.
给屁屁来个日式按摩
Bring this puppy up to a little shiatsu.
- 摩斯密码 不会吧  - 保持新鲜感
- Morse code? Really? - Keeping it fresh.
啊哈 下回是啥 烟雾信号吗
Uh-huh. What's next, smoke signals?
别想
Don't.
是啥案子
What do we have?
今早在一个能源研究机构
A, uh, robbery and a shooting early this morning
发生的一个抢劫和枪战
at a Department of Energy research facility.
保安是一个退伍的
The security guard is retired
海军陆战队射击中士Dennis Martin
Marine Gunnery Sergeant Dennis Martin.
他现在在加州洛杉矶分院做手术
He is currently in surgery at UCLA.
保安开了两枪 正中红心
The guard got off two shots, center mass.
不知道枪手穿了防弹衣
Didn't know the shooter was wearing a vest.
他们偷了什么
What'd they steal?
美国MINDS的位置
The United States MINDS locations.
政府思想控制吗
As in governmental mind-control?
是MINDS
As in MINDS.
微型集成核探测系统
Miniature Integrated Nuclear Detection System.
那是个反恐设备 能够定位和检测出辐射源
It's an antiterrorism device that can locate and detect
也能用于制作核弹
sources of radiation that could be used in a nuclear bomb.
威慑坏蛋们的是
What makes it a deterrent for bad guys
这个设备不引人注意 能放置在任何地方
is that it's unobtrusive and can be anywhere--
建筑物的大堂
building lobbies,
火车站 全国各地的入口处
train stations, entry gates across the country.
如果恐怖主义分子知道传感器在哪儿
If terrorists know where the sensors are,
他们就能把核弹头运过
they can transport a nuclear device
一个城市而不被发现
through a U.S. City undetected.
来了
Incoming.
Jones小姐 马上放一份案件资料
Ms. Jones, send a copy of the case information
在我的办公桌上
to my desk immediately.
明白
Copy that.
这怎么都不奇怪
No, this isn't weird at all.
我听到了 Deeks先生
I heard that, Mr. Deeks.
我敢肯定
I'm pretty sure
那个表情看透了我的灵魂
that look just pierced my soul.
关于那个死者 我们知道啥
What do we know about the dead guy?
Brody Stallworth
Brody Stallworth.
知名的入室抢劫犯 犯案累累
Long list of high-profile home robberies.
他能绕过大多数
He's bypassed most of
私营企业所提供的
the latest state-of-the-art security systems
最新最先进的安全系统
that the private sector has to offer.
- 另一个人呢  - 摩托车车手的身份未知
- And the other guy?  - No I.D. On the motorcyclist.
所以我们知道有个"偷盗大师' 然后还有个另一个"打酱油"的
So we have a "Master thief," And then we have the "Other guy."
我就说说 作为搭档
I'm just saying, for partners,
这显然是价值的失衡
it's clearly an imbalance of perceived value.
自尊心受挫 是吗
Running low on self-esteem, are we?
也许吧
Maybe.
另一个人骑着摩托车跑了
The "Other guy" Got away on his motorcycle.
看样子他中了一枪
Looks like he took a bullet.
他很有可能寻求医疗救助
And he's probably looking for medical attention.
是的
Right.
我去查医院
I'll check the hospitals.
Stallworth最后已知的地址是
And Stallworth's last known address
在北好莱坞
was in North Hollywood.
我刚刚已经发到你们的智能手机上了
I've just downloaded it to your smartphones.
Sam和我去查看Stallworth的住处
Sam and I will check out Stallworth's place.
Kensi 你为啥不去和那
Kensi, why don't you and the, uh,
"打酱油的"去调查能源部
"Other guy" Check out the Department of Energy,
看看有什么发现
see what you can find.
- 当然  - "打酱油的" 好极了
- Of course.  - The "Other guy, that's great.
你为什么就不能拿走我剩余的灵魂啊
Just take the rest of my soul, why don't you.
联邦探员
Federal agents!
安全
Clear.
安全 G 这儿
Clear! G, down here!
哈
Huh.
你对这些工具嫉妒吗
You having a little tool envy?
没有
Hardly.
但是这个相当令人佩服啊
But this is impressive.
这些人绝对知道自己要干嘛
These guys definitely knew what they were doing.
他们自己定制偷盗工具
They were building custom tools for their jobs.
貌似他们用暖通空调公司的名义
It looks like they were using the cover of an HVAC company
拿到了目标建筑的设计图
to get the layout of their targets.
我知道你这表情代表啥
I know that look.
这不科学
It just doesn't make sense.
我知道这些人
I understand these guys
做他们擅长的事情
were skilled at what they do...
有好工具帮忙
The right tools help.
但他们作为飞贼引以为傲
But they're glorified cat burglars.
这可是蓝领级的行动 手工活来的
It's a blue-collar operation, it's hands-on,
但想想 为啥偷能源部
but think about it, the Department of Energy?
这可是远远超过他们的薪酬级别
Mm. It's way above their pay grade.
那可不是他们典型的入室盗窃手法
That is not your typical B-and-E.
嗯
Hmm.
貌似他有个停车位
Looks like he splurged for parking.
我们去看看
Let's check it out.
你想猜一猜是哪个吗
You care to take a guess?
那个
That one.
猜得好
Good guess.
他回家就被杀
Guess he came home to die.
在录像里 他只被打中了肩膀
In the video, he was shot only once in the his shoulder.
他身上有三个近身枪伤
He has three close-range wounds to the torso.
看这个血迹喷溅型态
Look at the blood spatter.
杀手跟踪他回来的
He tracked him back
- 来灭口  - 或者
- to finish the job.  - Or...
凶手知道他会回来这儿
our shooter knew he was coming back here.
虎头蛇尾
Tied up loose ends.
G
G.
说茄子
Say "Cheese."
可能拍到了凶手
Might have gotten a shot of our guy.
我让神奇双胞胎来调查
I'll get the Wonder Twins on it.
他们从通风通道进来的
They came in through the ventilation system.
他们通过通风管道 跳到这个电脑的前方
They navigated the ductwork and dropped down in front of this station.
这层楼有多少这样的管道
How many systems on this floor?
- 呃 大概四十个  - 所以他们闯入这里
- Uh, maybe 40.  - So they break in,
他们俨然知道自己该黑哪个电脑
they know exactly which station to hack?
电脑系统没有被黑
The system wasn't hacked.
是正常登录的
It was accessed normally.
这就是为什么安保警报没有响 每台电脑需要
That's why no security was tripped. Every station needs
自己的密码登录他们的系统
a personal passkey to log on to their specific system.
这是谁的电脑
Whose station is this?
Roy Kessler的
Uh, Roy Kessler's.
但Roy是个好人
But Roy is a great guy.
让我猜猜
Let me guess,
好人会在周五的时候去喝玛格丽特酒
great guy that buys margaritas on Fridays?
- 嗯  - 然后今天还没有来上班
- Hm?  - And then didn't show up for work today.
事实上
As a matter of fact...
我需要他的住址
I'm gonna need his address.
我去打电话
I'm gonna call it in.
Roy Kessler订了一班离开Burbank的飞机
Roy Kessler has a flight booked out of Burbank,
你要赶快 他用了叫车服务
but you better hurry-- he's hired a car service
在二十分钟内接他去机场
to pick him up in 20 minutes.
好吧 Roy 让我们看看你带了啥
Okay, Roy, let's see what you got in here.
两条宽松裤
Two pair of slacks.
T恤
T-shirt.
出生证明
Birth certificate.
你去纽约就只准备带这些东西
You're taking a trip to New York and this is all you pack?
行程很匆忙吗
Are you in a rush?
我不了解你 但我去趟山谷都带了超多东西
I don't know about you, but I over-pack when I go to the valley.
也许他准备到那儿再买呢
Maybe he was gonna shop when he got there.
我能解释
I can explain.
我们知道你的钥匙被用于昨晚的抢劫
We know your passkey was used in the robbery last night.
你为什么要跑
Why were you running?
我知道这看上去像什么样...
I know how this looks...
我不认为你知道
I don't think you do.
好吧 听着...昨晚我和两个女孩在开派对
Okay, look... I was partying with these two girls last night.
我们不是一类人 但我想"泡她们" 好吗
Way out of my league. So I'm thinking working girls, right?
但那时我顾不了那么多
But at this point I could care less.
事情玩的有点过火
Things got a little crazy.
之后我只记得 我在家里醒来
Next thing I remember, I'm waking up at home.
独自一人
Alone.
我肯定是被下药了
I must have been drugged.
完全没照经典爱情故事的套路走啊
Nothing like a good old-fashioned honeypot.
直到我在新闻上看见抢劫的事
It wasn't until I heard about the robbery on the news
我才发现我的钥匙不见了
that I noticed that my passkey was missing.
所以你宁愿逃跑 也不愿意协助调查
So rather than help with the investigation, you decided to skip town.
我登录了系统检查窃贼们都看了什么东西 然后我慌了
I logged on to the system to see what the thieves accessed. I guess I panicked.
为什么
Why?
因为他们只拷走了部分MINDS的资料库
Because they only copied part of the MINDS databases.
哪部分的
Which part?
洛杉矶郡
Los Angeles County.
我们都很危险
We're all in danger.
所以我们从哪儿开始
Okay, so where do we even start?
挑选出最不可能的目标
Pinpointing a target's gonna be damn near impossible.
洛杉矶郡有4752平方英里
L.A. County's 4,752 square miles.
大海捞核啊
Got a nuke in a haystack.
我们不可能撤离整个郡的人
There's no way we can evacuate a whole county.
偷东西的人要么是为了赚钱
Whoever stole this thing is looking to make some coin,
要么就是到了恐怖袭击的最后阶段
or this is a terrorist attack in its final stage.
Stallworth的安全监控有好消息了
Well, the security camera from Stallworth's garage paid off.
枪手进入小巷的时候戴着滑雪面具
Our shooter entered the alley wearing a ski mask.
不好意思 这算啥子好消息
I'm sorry, how is that a payoff?
我们想着如果有人带着滑雪面具走来走去
Well, we figured someone walking around
一定会引起注意 所以我们查看了整个区域
in a ski mask would draw attention, so we scanned the area,
发现他在两个街区外用过付费电话
and we found him using a pay phone two blocks away.
一样的衣服 一样的身材 没戴面具
Same clothes, same build, no ski mask.
好吧 说真的 这年头谁还会用付费电话啊
Okay, honestly, who still uses a pay phone?
我宁愿去亲白脸猴也不要用付费电话
I'd rather kiss the Outbreak monkey than use a pay phone.
你是洁癖? 我可是见过你的公寓
How are you a germaphobe? I've seen your apartment.
哥对自己的细菌可没意见 而你 还有你们
Okay, I'm fine with my own germs, and you, of all people,
都不应雇家居清洁服务 我可是见过他们的清洁箱
should not be giving housekeeping notes. I've seen cleaner litter boxes.
喵~~
Oh, meow.
身份查到了吗
We got an I.D.?
没 面部识别还没有结果
No. Nothing through facial rec yet.
我去看看能否从那投币细菌培养皿
I'll see if the boys in blue
找到识别用图片
can pull a print off that coin-operated petri dish.
还记得我给你的口香糖吗
Remember that gum I gave you?
- 捡起来给你前掉浴室地板上了  - 一点都不好笑
- Dropped it on the bathroom floor first. - That's not funny.
伙计们 枪炮军士Martin
Guys. Gunnery Sergeant Martin,
能源部的警卫 他刚做完手术 已经醒了
the D.O.E. Security guard, he just got out of surgery. He's conscious.
我去过两次中东 却在自家土地上被人枪击
Two tours in the Middle East, and I get shot at home.
还是当警卫被枪击的
And working as a security guard, no less.
- 你该庆幸你还活着  - 我可不这么确定
- You're lucky to be alive. - I'm not so sure about that.
子弹伤到了脊椎
Bullet nicked my spine.
医生不确定我还能不能走路
Doc's not sure I'm gonna walk again.
那就证明他们是错的
Then you prove them wrong.
你是个海军 海军就该这么做
You're a Marine; that's what you do.
好勒
Oorah to that.
关于事情经过 你有什么能告诉我们的吗
Is there anything else you can tell us about what happened?
给我手机
Uh... give me the phone.
你有线索
You got something?
我看见枪手开车跑了
I saw the shooter drive away.
晕过去之前试图拍了几张照片
Tried to snap a shot before I blacked out.
很棒的线索
This is a great lead.
海军训练的结果
Call it Marine training.
真是"好勒"
Oorah, indeed.
我听说你调出了Griffin的档案
I heard you pulled the Griffin file.
你是为这个来的吗
Is that why you're here?
还因为有个可能威胁洛杉矶郡的核弹这件小事吧
Well, that and the small matter of a possible nuclear bomb threatening L.A. County.
你认为Griffin是幕后黑手
You think Griffin's behind it?
我希望不是
I hope not.
这说得通
It makes sense.
几年前他们开始核侦测项目的时候
We suspected Griffin's team of selling secrets
我们就怀疑Griffin的团队在售卖机密
when they initiated the nuclear detection program years ago.
是的 但我们没有证据
Yes, but we couldn't prove anything.
但不代表他是无辜的
Doesn't mean he wasn't guilty.
你的调查毁了他的事业
Your investigation cost him his career.
他放纵的生活方式毁了他的事业
His destructive lifestyle cost him his career.
当然了
Of course.
你还在怪罪我放他走了
You still blame me for letting him go.
我怪或不怪都不重要
Whether I do or don't is irrelevant.
重点是 如果Griffin是核袭击的幕后黑手
What matters is, if Griffin's behind a nuclear attack,
从海军部长到总司令都必然会怪罪于你
everyone from the SECNAV to the Commander in Chief most certainly will blame you.
这样的话 Henrietta
And that, Henrietta,
你这事业生涯就完了
will be the end of your career.
查到什么没
What do you got?
你们会给Martin军士
You may want to send
送个致谢花篮的 他手机上的照片
Gunnery Sergeant Martin an Edible Arrangement-- footage
传过来了
from his mobile device came through.
我可爱死这个了
I love those things.
奇异果是各种动物的形状
I get the kiwis in the shape of the animals,
我就装成狮子 扮成...
and I pretend I'm a lion, and I'm, like...
你才知道你话说多了点
You realize you're talking out loud, right?
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
万花筒系统找到了枪手
Kaleidoscope got a hit on the shooters' plates.
- 在哪里  - 他人现在不在那里 可是...
- Where? - It's gone now, but...
一小时之前 那辆车就停在Echo公园的一个库房边上
an hour ago, the car was parked at a warehouse in Echo Park.
Callen和Sam已经在过去的路上了
Callen and Sam are already en route.
告诉他们我们也过去
Tell them we're on the way.
Kensi和Deeks
Kensi and Deeks
也在过来的路上了
are on their way.
锁上了 让我来
It's locked. I got it.
安全
Clear.
啊哦
Well...
我就知道在古文字课上逃课迟早有报应
I knew skipping that hieroglyphics class goona come back to bite me
你觉得这些大头钉代表什么
What do you think the pins represent?
太多了 不像是MINDS的部署位置
There's too many to be MINDS locations.
这里一定有破解这些的东西
Has to be a key around here somewhere to decipher it.
哇哦 兄弟们 自己人
Whoa! Whoa, man. We're on your side.
我告诉我们进来的时候
I told you to send them an alert
- 跟他们说一声  - 我说了
- when we were coming in. - I did.
看 终于接到短信了
Oh! There it is.
不是我的错哦
It's not my fault
我们都到了 他们还没接到通知呢
we move faster than the speed of cellular.
我找到了点东西
I got something here.
是什么
What is it?
钴60的运输路线
It's routing information for cobalt 60.
- 这东西可是医学级同的同位素  - 医学级的
- That's medical- grade isotope. - Medical-grade?
那现在我们要解决的就不是核弹爆炸
That means we're not talking about a nuclear explosion.
当然不是 钴60是用来做脏弹的
No, cobalt 60's something you'd use to make a dirty bomb.
这东西炸响了
The blast waves from the explosion would be more lethal
可比辐射更要命
than a radioactive explosion.
他想吓唬人
He's trying to scare 'em.
心理上的恐吓
This is all about psychological harm.
想想看
Think about it.
大规模的骚乱...
Mass panic...
经济受损 恐慌
economic damage, terror.
这才不是大规模杀伤性武器
This isn't a weapon of mass destruction,
这会使国家分崩离析
it's a weapon of mass disruption.
这些标记都可能是钴60的位置
So these markers could all be cobalt 60 locations.
是啊 可这里看不出这些地方是哪里
Yeah, but there's no way to tell what these locations are.
Kensi 你和Deeks
Kensi, why don't you and Deeks focus
去查这个运输路线 看看这些大头针
on this routing information,see if you can pin point
指向能否指出钴60的来源
where this cobalt 60 came from.
这就去办
On it.
这东西没用
It's useless.
要是这家伙能搞到原料做脏弹
If this guy was able to secure materials
我们的时间就不够了
to make a dirty bomb, we may already be out of time.
想见我
You wanted to see me?
进度如何
How we doing?
嗯 仓库没人 不过拿到了不少情报
Well, nobody in the warehouse, but lots of intel.
我们正在尝试破译
We're trying to decipher it as we speak.
我正要过去看看能不能拿到第一手资料
I'm about to go on-site to get a firsthand look.
让Beale先生去吧
Send Mr. Beale.
好的
Okay.
我要知道这个人现在在哪里
I need to know where this man is.
Kelvin C. Griffin
Kelvin C. Griffin.
和这个案子有关
Is he involved in the case?
我希望不是
I hope not.
这件事情优先去做
This is priority one.
停下其它的事情 只要找到他
Drop everything. Find him.
我这就去做
I'll get right on it.
Nell
Nell?
结果只准我看
For my eyes only.
那是自然
Of course.
我们还是忘了什么
We're missing something.
除非奇迹出现 我们无计可施
It's impossible without the legend.
我来了 不过我可不是奇迹哦
I'm good, but I'm hardly a legend.
Nell呢
Where's Nell?
我还以为你会问"Eric 你怎么找到那个枪手的"
I think the question is, "Eric, how did you get an I.D.
答案是
on the shooter?" Answer:
我进入了CIA的数据库
I was granted access
作为交换
to the CIA database. In exchange
我以后要帮他们几个忙 别问是什么
for favors to be called in later. Don't ask.
就这个
Really?
是个...图像密码
Just a... picture password.
Ferat Hadad
Ferat Hadad.
他是叙利亚特种部队
He's a member
As-Sai'qa的成员
of As-Sai'qa.
叙利亚特种部队
Syrian special forces.
CIA那边可是什么都没说 不过我觉得
The CIA isn't talking, but you get the impression
他们可是很想抓住这家伙
that they want him real bad.
一个叙利亚的特种兵
So, a Syrian commando
手里拿着美国MINDS系统的部署图
has in his possession U.S. MINDS locations.
那他下一步要做什么
What's his next move?
不破解这个就没法知道
We may never know if we have to decipher all this first.
好吧 让我来
Well, allow me.
哦
Huh.
嗯 好吧 很有趣
Yeah. Okay, interesting.
非常有趣
Very interesting.
什么意思
What does it mean?
没有头绪
Not a clue.
我连进了
Oh, I'm patched in
能源部的安全系统
to the D.O.E. Security system.
- 他们收到了一个MINDS警报  - 在哪里
- They just got a MINDS alert. - Where?
呃 市中心的Grand Park
Uh, Grand Park. Downtown.
等一下
Hold on a second.
那他怎么办 我们不能把他丢在这里
What are we doing with him? We can't leave him here alone.
没事
He's not.
我来掩护
I'm the backup.
我们能问问题吗
Should we ask?
不行 赶紧出发吧
No. You should go, quickly.
嗨
Hi.
嗯 看起来挺平静的
Well, it looks pretty quiet.
我连卖培根包热狗的人
I don't even see the dude selling death by hot dog
- 都没见到  - 有可能是假警报吗
- wrapped in bacon. - Possible false alarm?
不对 是有什么东西引发了警报的
No, something set off that alarm.
这感觉就不对劲
This just doesn't feel right.
偷走了这技术的人肯定知道我们在看着警报的
Whoever stole that tech had to know we'd be on alert.
- 这可能是个陷进  - 没错 但不管
- This could be a setup. - That's true, but if there's
可能性有多小 我们都得查清楚
the slightest chance it's legit, we got to check it out.
好吧 我们分头行动
Right. Let's split up
清查这片区域
and sweep the area.
注意别人遗弃的物品 检查垃圾桶周围
Look for anything abandoned-- check the trash cans,
还有任何被人留下的东西
search for anything deserted.
明白了
Got it.
也有可能在某个人身上
Could be on someone's person.
你是说类似炸弹背心那样吗
You mean like a bomb vest?
那里 穿着米黄色外套的家伙
There. Guy in the beige jacket.
是Hadad
It's Hadad.
他在等人的样子
He's looking for somebody.
他开始移动了
He's on the move.
我从右边包抄
I'll take the right flank.
别动 我是联邦探员
Stop! Federal agents!
都结束了
It's over!
快放她走
Let her go.
马上放下武器
Drop your weapon! Now!
别开枪
Don't do it.
千万别开枪
Do not do it.
Hadad
Hadad!
跟我来吧
Come with me.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
我们是联邦探员 你现在安全了
We're federal agents. You're safe.
噢 天啊
Oh, my God...
没找到炸弹
No bomb.
Callen
Callen.
我猜你没想过要试着把他活捉吧
I don't suppose it occurred to you to try and take him alive?
他手上有人质
He had a hostage.
Hetty在哪里
Where's Hetty?
跟Beale呆在一起
With Beale.
怎么了 发生什么事了
Why? What's going on?
没有你想知道的事
Nothing you want to know about.
看这里
Check it out.
西门口 两点钟
West doors, 2:00,
穿着灰西服 觉得他们是要见面呢
gray suit. Think they're having a meeting,
还是他在跟踪他
or you think he was following him?
Hadad这样的人
Guy like Hadad?
是来这里干掉他的
He was here to take him out.
也许Nell可以
Maybe Nell can...
找出他的身份
tell us who he is.
Hadad没有穿炸弹背心 那是什么触发了MINDS警报
Hadad's not wearing a bomb vest, so what set off the MINDS alert?
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 能借来用一下吗  - 当然
- Can I borrow this? - Sure.
谢了
Thank you.
不好意思 伙计们
Excuse me, guys.
很微弱的剂量
It's weak,
不过还是有反应
but it's positive.
你找到什么了
Did you find something?
钴60 这家伙衣服上都沾满了
Cobalt 60. The guy's clothes are covered in it.
- 呃  - 放松
- Uh... - Relax.
这比我们每天接触到的剂量还要少
It's less than what we're exposed to on a daily basis,
不过也足够触发感测器了
but it was enough to set the sensors off.
我们还是赶紧洗个澡好吧
We should probably still take a shower.
我知道杂志上这家伙的身份了
I got a positive I.D. On our magazine guy.
Richard Towson
The guy's name is Richard Towson.
他是在俄亥俄州东克利夫兰的一名商人
He's a businessman in East Cleveland, Ohio.
俄亥俄 那他在洛杉矶干什么
Ohio? What's he doing in Los Angeles?
他不在这
He's not.
他还在俄亥俄
He's still in Ohio.
Hadad在这里追杀一个
Hadad was targeting a man
两千里之外的人 完全说不通啊
2,000 miles away-- it makes no sense.
假如Hadad是被设计来
It might if Hadad was set up
触发这些探测器的话 这也许就说通了 他们在测算我们的反应方案
to trigger the sensors-- they're gauging our protocol.
空旷的地方
Wide-open space...
可能有大量平民
possibility of large groups of people.
反应时间 联邦探员出动
Response times, agencies,
装置敏感度
device sensitivity.
这是一次测试
It's a test.
好吧 如果他愿意浪费
Well, so if he's willing to sacrifice
- 放射性材料来做一次测试  - 那么他就
- radioactive material on a test...  - It stands to reason
更有可能做了一个真正的脏弹了
he has more to make an actual dirty bomb.
没错
Right.
很好
Wonderful.
我去 这没道理
Damn, it makes no sense.
每次我以为快找到模式的时候 它就又改变了
Every time I think I'm close, the pattern changes.
这里实在有太多点了
There are just too many pins.
坚持下去 Beale先生
Persistence, Mr. Beale.
我已经试过所有已知的破解密码的方程了
I've tried every code-cracking formula known to man.
或许你该试一下女人知道的方法
Maybe it's time to try those known to women.
你是在暗示Nell
Are you suggesting that Nell
比我在这方面更厉害吗
is better at these sort of things?
她是吗
Is she?
我可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question,
Hetty
Hetty?
我还是宁愿
I'd probably prefer
你专注于眼前的任务吧
you focus on the task at hand.
你为什么会在这里
Why are you here?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
一切都好吗
Is everything okay?
其实 呃 有可能
It's, uh, possible...
在这事情的幕后黑手
that the man who's behind this
是一个曾经
is someone who once...
逃出我手掌心的人
slipped through my fingers.
那糟透了
That sucks.
没错
Indeed.
嗯 这看起来有点希望
Hmm, this looks promising.
你王八儿子的密码就在这
You sneaky son of a cipher.
这是什么
What are we looking at?
这是整个
It's a map...
- 西海岸的地图  - 那这个是干嘛的
- of the entire West Coast. - Let's see what this one does.
这是用颜色来区分
It's color-coded.
黄色棋子沿着黄色边界走
Yellow flags go with the yellow border.
还有这个
And this one.
我最靠谱的想法是 这些大头针指着
My best guess is, these pins represent
从圣地亚哥一路到西雅图
vulnerable targets from San Diego
所有守卫薄弱的目标
all the way up to Seattle.
那红色旗子呢
And the red flags?
这些沿着红色边界走
They go with the red border.
旗子代表的是他的目标
The flags must represent his targets.
这一次
Which, in this case,
则是洛杉矶市中心半径一英里的范围
is a one-mile radius of downtown Los Angeles.
我们在和FBI 洛杉矶警局
We're coordinating with FBI, LAPD
还有核紧急事态搜寻队协调当中了 部长先生
and the NEST teams, Mr. Secretary.
我们已经接近他们了
We're closing in on them.
一有消息就会通知你的 先生
The moment we do, sir.
告诉我我们有所进展吧
Tell me we got something.
确定了市中心半径一英里的范围
A one-mile radius around downtown
还是有几百个潜在目标可能受到袭击
still leaves hundreds of potential targets.
我们在确定袭击目标上跟
And we're no closer to finding the target
找到设计Hadad的人一样毫无进展
than we are to finding the guy who set up Hadad.
这说不通 原本这次就可以发动袭击了
Doesn't add up. This could've been the attack.
为什么还要等
Why wait?
可能是想转移视线
Could be a diversion.
那我们还应该注意找些什么
So what else in the area should we be looking at?
不是我们要找什么
It's not what we're looking at,
而是谁在注意我们
it's what's looking at us.
想一想
Think about it.
如果你来做这个测试
If this is your test,
你怎么知道有没有成功
how do you know if you're successful?
没错 慢慢散开
All right, fan out.
我们要找一个局外围观的人
We're looking for an outlier.
听起来就像个偷窥狂 从远处观察
Sounds like a voyeur-- they observe from a distance,
长焦镜头 双面镜
telephoto lens, two-way mirrors.
有什么想说的吗 Deeks
Something you want to tell me, Deeks?
不要理趴在你浴室窗台
Just ignore the garden gnome
- 的小地精好了  - 好了 现在
- outside your bedroom window.  - Okay. Now,
我们能连进应急部队的俯视镜头吗
can we get a bird's-eye view of the response teams?
我想我们要找的人可能就藏在最明显的地方
We're thinking our guy might be hiding in plain sight.
好了 我连进了周围的几个监控镜头
Okay, I've got eyes on the area from multiple feeds.
看一下
Let's see.
在Hill街的东南角
Southeast corner of Hill Street,
有一个穿着核紧急事态搜寻队外套的男人
there's a man in a NEST windbreaker.
他一直站在警戒范围以外
He's standing just outside the police perimeter.
Nell 我们没看到他
Nell, we don't see him.
找到了
Got him.
噢 靠
Oh, boy.
怎么啦 Nell
What is it, Nell?
额 没事
Uh, it's nothing.
他走进了地铁站
Uh, he is heading down into the metro station.
Kensi Deeks 去西边的入口
Kensi, Deeks, move to the west entrance.
我们夹击他
We'll flush him to you.
记住要活捉
Remember to take him alive.
快点让开
Move! Out of the way!
不好意思
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
让开 让开
Move! Move!
找到他了
We got him.
- 联邦探员 停下来  - 嚓
- Federal agents! Stop! - Damn it!
快点 快点
Come on! Come on!
快上来 快点 快啊
Come on, come on, come on!
这就是我为啥讨厌坐地铁了
This is why I hate taking the subway.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
嗯
Yeah.
就是你这鸡婆毁了我的一生
You're the stump that ruined my life.
Hetty认识这家伙吗
Hetty knows this guy?
她放过他了一次
She let him go once.
有人告诉我她不会再犯
Something tells me she's not gonna make
同一个错误了
that mistake again.
你发誓说你是无辜的
You swore you were innocent.
你对我发誓的
You swore to me,
可是我们还是又在这里见面了
and yet here we are again.
你帮助研发
You helped develop the, uh,
这个监测项目来保卫这个国家
detection program to defend the country.
来保护
To protect...
人们
people...
例如你的孩子
like your own children.
你曾经是一名爱国者啊
You were a patriot.
但在某地方 你迷失了自我
Somewhere, you lost your way.
我们每个人都会或多或少遇到这种事情
It happens to all of us...at some point.
这不会为你所做的事情做出补偿
This won't make up for what you've done,
但这是必须要走的一步
but it's a step.
而你还是能拯救生命
And you can still...save lives.
目标是什么
What is the target?
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得你还没明白
I don't think you understand.
一切都结束了
It's... over.
我只是测试场景
I was just running scenarios...
收集数据
collecting data.
我需要钱
I needed the money.
我不知道他们的目标是什么
I don't know their target.
- 他们的吗 - 是啊 在Hancock公园有个屋子
- "Their"?  - Yeah. There's a house in Hancock Park,
属于俄罗斯领事馆
and it belongs to the Russian Consulate.
那个数据 被加密了
The data, it's encrypted,
但它拖不了他们那么久的
but it won't take them that long.
你把我们的核侦测技术
You sold our nuclear detection technology
卖给俄罗斯了吗
to the Russians?
当你觉得冷战已经结束的时候
Just when you thought the Cold War was over.
还远着呢
Not even close.
所以 我们现在干嘛
So, what are we gonna do now?
为你的职业生涯没有结束高兴一下
Be happy your career's not over.
这不是Hetty的错
This is not Hetty's fault.
已经不重要了
Doesn't matter.
在这个游戏里 Blye探员
In this game, Agent Blye,
总要有人背黑锅的
somebody always takes the blame.
总要有些事是我们可以做的
There has got to be something that we can do.
现在这是白宫的噩梦了
This is an Oval Office nightmare now.
俄罗斯人想要从洛杉矶的核探测系统
What do the Russians want
中得到什么
with L.A.'s nuclear detection system?
冷战在发酵
The Cold War's heating up.
朋友或敌人 国家之间都相互收集信息
Friend or foe, nations collect intel on each other.
不知道什么时候他们会用上它
Never know when they'll need or use it.
- 或者分享  - 嘿 伙计们
- Or share it. - Hey, guys.
确定Griffin指认的那套房子属于
The house Griffin identified
俄罗斯领事馆
does indeed belong to the Russian Consulate.
这意味着它是外国领土
Which means it's considered foreign soil.
所以我们不能破门而入
So we can't just bang on the door
然后告诉他们交出来吗
and tell them to hand it over?
不造成国际事件下不行
Not without causing an international incident.
你被抓了才是国际事件
It's only an international incident if you get caught.
哇 不 剧透警报
Whoa. No. Spoiler alert.
我不想听到这个
I do not want to hear this.
捂上耳朵
Uh, cover your ears.
我们在一国的 Beale
We're all in this together, Beale.
想想这个 G
Think about this, G.
闯进外国领事馆
Breaking into a foreign consulate,
这个行动 一旦我们被抓到
an action which, if we're caught...
政府就会否认我们的存在
forces our government to disavow us.
如果你们不想被卷进来 我能理解
I understand if you don't want to be involved in this one.
你说什么呢 我加入
What are you talking about? I'm in.
我在讨论他们
I'm talking about them.
我们不那么做 我们就会失去Hetty
We don't do this, we lose Hetty.
我们加入
We are in.
是Hetty
Yeah, it's Hetty.
顺便说一句 如果Kensi去 我也去
Besides, if Kensi goes, I go.
这就是我们的相处之道
That's how we roll.
你知道我们这次行动不受保护吧
You realize we're off the reservation with this one.
我们都可能受到指控
We could all be subject to criminal charges.
俄罗斯会试图引渡我们
Russia may even try and extradite us.
还没去过俄罗斯
Never been to Russia.
我听说古拉格每年这个时候都风景不错
I hear the Gulags are lovely this time of year.
哈喽 我是南方天然气公司的
Hello. I'm with the South Hills Gas Company.
有事吗
Yes?
这里有一个地震三角带
There's a been a quake-- three-pointer.
我感觉不到任何事
I didn't feel anything.
哦 是的 说明你已经习惯了
Ooh, yeah, that means you're getting used to it.
你知道 就我个人而言 6级以下的小震
You know, personally, I don't get out of bed
我都懒得下床
for anything less than a six-banger.
知道我说什么呢吗
Know what I'm saying?
不 我不知道
No, I don't.
不管怎样 我们发现一个七级的煤气泄漏
Anyhoo, we have a class-seven gas main leak,.
作为安全防护措施 我们要疏散人群
We're evacuating people as a safety precaution.
- 我们不会的  - 好吧 额 Fern
- We will not. - Okay, uh, Fern,
我这里有超过五级的
I'm getting some serious class-five
氢的读数 所以我们应该
hydrogen readings here, so we should probably...
什么玩意 Fern
What the hell, Fern!
你们这些人怎么还在这里
What are these people still doing here?
这玩意儿分分钟有可能爆炸
This thing could blow up at any second.
你想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
他不想离开这里 这是个自由的国家
He won't leave. It's a free country.
他们不想离开这是因为 你从哪里来 先生
They won't leave 'cause it's... Where you from, sir?
Vladivostok
Vladivostok.
Vladi... vos.. 好吧 听着 我不知道那是哪里
Vladi... vos... Okay, listen, I don't know where that is,
但是这里是美国 这房子底下
but here in America, we have a hydrogen pipe
铺设了氢气管道
running right underneath this house,
除非你想在爆炸时
and unless you want to be inside of it
待在里面 否则我建议你离开
when it blows up, I suggest you vacate.
好吧 就这么着吧 如果他被炸上天了
Okay, you know what, if he blows up,
全都怪你 让他签免责协议
this is on you-- have him sign a waiver.
洛杉矶这座城市依旧在Hancock
The city of Los Angeles is still recovering
公园的强烈地震恢复的过程中
from an earthquake that struck the Hancock Park area...
给我们一点时间
Give us a few moments.
伙计们 五区停电了
Guys, we got a power outage in sector five.
等一下
Hold on.
收到 五区
Copy that, sector five.
伙计们 我们得走了 来吧
我们走 走啊
Let's go, let's go.
有人在屋里吗 先生
Is that everybody in the house, sir?
要多久才能好
How long this will take?
我希望不要太久
Hopefully, not long.
幽灵1和2号 可以起行
Phantom 1 and 2, you're a go.
目标朝你去了
Bogey headed your way.
我看到他了
I got him.
这得要多久才好
至少还有30分钟
不 我们现在得走了
我没完成呢
你可以在飞机上继续
他们准备离开
They're moving the drives.
现在不动手就没机会了
It's now or never.
我会吸引他的注意力
I'll draw him to me.
低调点
Make it quiet.
速战速决
Make it fast.
真是太低调了
So much for quiet.
伙计们 我们这里有余震
Guys, we've got some aftershock activity going on here.
派些穿梭巴士来带走这些人
Let's get those shuttles in to clear these folks out.
先生 抱歉 在我得到命令之前
sir, sorry, I can't let you back in there
我不能让你进去
until I have authorization.
滚开
Get out of my way.
这就是你低调的方式吗
That's your idea of quiet?
- 你有快的方法吗  - 但愿你能搞定这个橱柜
Was that your idea of fast?  - Hope you can fix that cabinet.
不 这需要一个专业的
No, that's definitely gonna take a professional.
伙计们 时间到了
Guys, time's up.
他们准备进来了
They're coming back in.
快点上楼
你叫了穿梭巴士吗
You call for a shuttle?
- 好了吗  - 还没
- We good? - Not yet.
车在这里
Ride's here!
我们上
Let's go!
好了 快 快 快
Well, go, go, go!
洛杉矶警局报告在俄罗斯领事馆
LAPD reported a gunfight
附近有枪战
in the vicinity of the Russian Consulate.
最好别让我发现你
I better not find out you had s...
天哪 不要
God, no.
告诉我你们没干
Tell me you didn't.
没干什么
Didn't what?
再耍花腔否认也救不了你
Plausible deniability won't save you.
你批准了吗
And you sanctioned this?
我一直在这里跟你在一起 Owen
I've been here with you, Owen.
你们知道你们干了什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've done?
拿回我们的科技
Retrieved our technology?
让世界更美好吗
Made the world a better place?
还要干得漂亮
And looked good while doing it.
这会毁了我们跟俄罗斯的关系
This is gonna destroy our relationship with the Russians.
他们不先承认偷窃
They can't make any accusations
就没办法做出任何指控
without admitting they stole it in the first place.
是的 部长先生
Yes, Mr. Secretary.
不 先生
No, sir.
不 先生 事情不完全是那样的
No, sir, that's not quite how it went down.
你还好吗 Hetty
You good, Hetty?
好极了
Just dandy.
我明白
I understand.
你觉得我们在做我们该做的事情的时候
How many lives do you think we've ruined
毁掉了多少生命
doing what we do?
谢谢你 部长先生
Thank you, Mr. Secretary.
比不上我们救了的
Not nearly as many as we've saved.
你在这点上躲过去了
Well... you dodged the bullet on this one.
如果你再发生这种事情
But if any of you ever pull something like this again...
你们都会受应得惩罚的
You all deserve each other.
我也这样想的
I certainly like to think so.
有人要喝伏特加吗
Anyone for a vodka?
== Deeks你是妇唱夫随吗 ==
== Eric你还能更娇弱点吗 ==
== 我爱死这种出生入死的团队了 ==
== 为了Hetty你们真是勇敢啊 ==
== Deeks果然还在作死 不过应该也有吃药 ==
== 【H-SGDK】字幕组欢迎各位加入
有意者请加QQ群109164858，注明 字幕组+申请职位即可 ==
== 海军罪案调查处:洛杉矶 第五季 第8集【H-SGDK】字幕组倾情奉献 ==
TMI Too Much Information
顺便拿走尊严吧
出自1995年美国电影"极度恐慌"
白脸猴将致命病毒传染人类带来极大灾难
Edible Arrangement这种水果篮会把水果切成各种形状
古拉格 前苏联政府一部 负责管理全国牢狱营
K姐又黄暴了
人家说的是海参崴 俄罗斯滨海边疆区首府
双关 你们值得拥有彼此